Peigeng Jiang

(+61) 499-482-349 • jiangpeigeng@gmail.com • Visa type: Temporary graduate visa 485

GitHub: https://github.com/AndyJPG • Website: https://andyjpg.github.io/

OBJECTIVE

Aim to work as a developer. Have experience in building SaaS application using mainly React and Node JS. Providing solutions to fix application issues and improve performance. Emphasize continuous integration and development while building application. Automated calculation process with Python to increase the efficiency of the company minimize human error by 80%. Have experience in Agile working environment and familiar with sprint planning, scrum meeting, and sprint retro. I believe my experience in software development and wide knowledge can be my advantage in applying for this job.

SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Git

Effective communication skill, Problem-solving, Teamwork, Presentation, Adaptability, Logical thinking, Time management

WORK EXPERIENCE

WordPress Developer Freelance

Design and develop website on WordPress.

Dec 2020 - Present Canberra, Australia

B&E Foods Jun 2020 - Nov 2020

A wholesale food supplier firm.

Melbourne, Australia

IT support

Major responsibilities including data analysis, website improvement, and communicating with stakeholders and team from other department to produce feasible IT solutions.

- Situation: The company website had a major performance issue that the website took around 30s to be fully loaded. The customer could only interact with the website after 16.3s, and the performance score on google was 16.
- **Task:** Evaluated website performance and code. Proposed findings and solutions to the team and implemented the solution.
- Action: I found the website had an excessive DOM size issue with 17000 DOM elements on its home page. Implemented the solution to remove the product display grid that loads a whole 500 products on the home page. Only remained some featured products on the home page.
- Result: Customers could interact with the website within 1.3s after improvement, and home page DOM size reduced to 800 elements. Website content fully loaded time from 36.7s before improvement reduced to 12.3s. The number of site visits increased by 50% in the following month after improvement and the site conversion rate increased by 70%. The website performance score improved to 80.
- Situation: The account team was unable to produce the desired customer statement data based on the current ERP system. Producing a single customer statement required login to the old system, searching, and printing. The whole process took around 3 minutes or longer. Seek for an alternative solution to calculate customer data and export data to a desired format.
- Task: Analyzed company's data structures and proposed solutions to the accounting team. Implemented the solution after planning.
- Action: Integrated Python with Excel, and used Xlwings add-in on excel to run external Python code. Implemented Python code to extract data and utilized libraries such as, pandas, NumPy, Xlwings for calculation, filtering, and aggregation process. Produced outcome in a desired format back to Excel for accountants to view more easily.
- Results: Minimized error in manual calculation and increased efficiency in the accounting department in terms of producing customer statements, invoices, and spotting statements issues. The process of producing a single customer statement only took around 5s or less after implementation.

CAFEEZY Oct 2019 - Jan 2020 Melbourne, Australia

A digital solution firm aims to provide an online platform for catering businesses.

Full-stack developer internship

Major responsibilities including bugs fixing and developing features. Building application follow company's code rules and standard, perform linting and testing before QA to enforce continuous integration. Manage AWS to create new instance for each version of application to achieve continuous development practice.

- Situation: Poor user experience resulted in React rendering mechanism. The website displayed users' input with 2s delay, which caused losing customers and receiving more user complain.
- Task: Researched and evaluated the issue, and proposed and presented at least 3 solutions to the supervisor. Implemented the solution that the team agreed on.

- Action: Searched similar issues online and listed potential causes. Examined React code with google development tool. Found a cause that React re-renders whole web content whenever the user inputs, which resulted in delay and lagging. Implemented the solution to separate the input event and prevent it from triggering web content to re-render.
- **Results:** Web application responded immediately to user input with zero waiting time. Major improvement in web application performance, which attracted more users to use the application and fewer user complains.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

OhFarm Application Project

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

Programmer

Melbourne

- **Situation**: The project was required to build an iOS application from scratch. The application obtained data served on AWS server and presented it to users after the processing. It also needed to implement a user management system to track user progress.
- Task: iOS application design and development. UI and UX design including application testing.
- Action: Organized and led the team to produce business and project plans. Produced plans at the beginning of each
 sprint to set goals and major functionalities. Developed iOS application with Swift using MVC model and library from
 CocoaPods. Had regular meetings with the team to discuss features implemented, and changed or improved based on
 feedback. Often communicated with designer regarding application UI design, and best practice to integrate design into
 application.
- Result: Application finalized and deployed within 3 months with positive feedbacks from users.
- Project link: github.com/AndyJPG/OhFarmV2.0.git

EDUCATION

Monash University

Jul 2017 - Jul 2019

Master Degree in Information Technology

Melbourne, Australia

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms and Data structures, Intelligent systems, Big data processing and management,
 Database analysis and processing, Business intelligence, Data warehousing, Software engineering